Contact

colinnebula@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/colinnebula-07176022 (LinkedIn) colinnebula3dartist.blogspot.ca (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Document Object Model (DOM) Node.js MongoDB

Languages

French

Colin Nebula

Full Stack Web Developer

Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Summary

IT Technical Support:

Dealing with customers in a professional manner while tending to their technological needs efficiently, has been a mainstay in my job description for over a decade. Trouble-shooting, reporting bugs, investigating, designing, and performing product tests were a daily requirement at my previous full-time job at Tira Wireless where I also gained deep insight into the development cycle of software. Currently, I provide a comprehensive array of technical services that generally involve managing issues and fixing the problem and then addressing the root causes to implement preventative strategies for the future. Setting benchmarks, maintaining licenses, and creating guidelines are other areas I have contributed to in both my full and part time jobs.

3D Generalist:

Classically trained in Art and able to transfer that into 3D using a host of software that are utilized industry-wide; Maya, 3D Studio Max, Fusion, Nuke, After Effects, Photoshop, Z Brush, etc.

Composited at Intelligent Creatures in Toronto for an internship!

Feature Films

3D Modeling, Texturing, UV mapping

Animation

Environments

VFX

TV Commercials

TV Shows

Specialties: 3D Modeling, Texturing, UV mapping, Compositing,

Rigging, Rotoscoping

Experience

Nebula Media.ca Creative Director August 2013 - Present (9 years 3 months)

Woodbridge Ontario

A host of responsibilities including but not limited to video production, 3D integration and video editing.

As well as, taking video games from storyboard and concept to the finish product.

Partsmart

Technical Support Consultant
December 2011 - Present (10 years 11 months)

Richmond Hill

- Network/Desktop support consultant with hardware and software application support, connectivity, and running reports to ensure smooth flow of operations for daily tasks
- Manage software licenses, maintain connections, troubleshoot hardware/ software issues
- Perform regular maintenance such as installations, updates, firewalls, virus protection,

OS setups and exceeding requirements in making the systems user-friendly for employees

Marvimation

Modeler and Texture Artist July 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Modeled a car (Toyota Supra)

Intelligent Creatures

Intern

September 2010 - November 2010 (3 months)

Modelling/Texturing

VFX responsibilities (compositing, rotoscoping, etc.)

TV Commercials

TV Shows

Tira Wireless

Quality Assurance - Mobile Game Platform

August 2007 - July 2008 (1 year)

Toronto

• Tested and logged bugs, addressed issues through JIRA workflow manager, conducted

field tests, regressions, developed strategies to reduce redundancies, and completed

general QA duties such as running reports and assisting the team in hitting weekly targets

• Set up a rotating schedule to improve team efficiency by assigning equipment for specific

periods to each team member to reduce dead time and exceed weekly testing targets

 Clients included companies such as Sony, ING, Hudson Soft, THQ, AccuWeather, each

with specific demands and multiple unique requests to account for in testing scenarios

Epson Printing

Technical Support-Inbound Call Centre December 2003 - January 2005 (1 year 2 months) Richmond Hill

- Provided troubleshooting for the complete product line, resolved complaints, ordered replacements for customers in a timely manner while up-selling other Epson products
- Conducted weekly reports, solved issues that required multi-department input and introduced ideas such as empowering the group with more tools to resolve complaints
- Maintained top performance numbers for accuracy and commended for punctuality

Advanced Brake Products

Computer Technician
June 2003 - August 2004 (1 year 3 months)

Toronto

 Set up multiple office computers and connected them to the network to share office

resources such as inventory systems, billings, production, and multiple sets of printers

• Provided considerable support in training and preparing staff for tasks on the

systems as well as set up security to prevent damage or loss of valuable information

• Performed routine tasks to keep the network and individual workstations problem-free

and was responsible for all software and hardware issues experienced by staff

Education

University of Toronto Coding Boot Comp Certificate, Web Development · (May 2021 - November 2021)

Centennial College

Digital Animation, Maya, 3DS Max, Zbrush, Fusion, Nuke, Photoshop, Live Drawing · (2009 - 2010)

Art Institute of Toronto

2D Art and 3D Game Design, Life drawing, 3DS Max, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Torque Game Engine · (2005 - 2007)